FRANKLIN SMITH

Software Engineer

EDUCATION

University of Oregon Graduation June 19' B.S. Computer Science

PROFILE

I am interested in working as a software engineer for a technology focused company that allows me to make a creative difference on a daily basis by applying my innovative insights, critical thinking, and programming capabilities to grow business and software product development. Skillset: Devops, Swift, C, C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, XHTML CSS, Node.js, Angular. Proficient with Swift and Cocoa Touch, XIB Files, storyboards, XCode and iOS SDK. Experience with iOS frameworks such as Core Location, Map kit, UlKit, Core Data. Experience with offline storage, threading, and performance tuning. Familiarity with RESTful APIs to connect to iOS applications to back-end services like firebase. Knowledge of Apple's design principles.

CONTACT

PHONE: 971-267-9409

WEBSITE:

https://fsmith503.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/franklin-smith-44340999/

FMAII:

fsmith4@uoregon.edu

HOBBIES

Reading Snowboarding Swimmina **Boating** Traveling

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wiline - Software Engineer June 2019 – Present

Responsible for building and maintaining Java applications. This includes anything between complex groups of back-end services and their client-end (desktop and mobile) counterparts. Designed and developed these applications and to coordinate with the rest of the team working on different layers of the infrastructure.

Knuckleheads Inc. - iOS Engineering intern March 2018 - September 2018

Designed and built advanced app features for the iOS platform, independently crafted project solutions by applying solid Object-Oriented-Design principles Worked in a team of talented iOS engineers developing amazing native apps. Worked closely with product management & UX to execute an idea from concept to delivery using excellent software design, coding, & processes.

FastModel Sports - Software Engineering Intern June 2017 - February 2018

Created, supported, modified, and tested internal company web application. Application provided critical internal company information on carousel style dashboard to users.

iTunes App Store Published iOS Software



Snowpack-

Created and engineered all software for iOS application Snowpack in Swift, currently available on apple iTunes app store. The most user-friendly app that provides real time snowfall conditions, weather reports, and resort updates for skier and snowboarders, for all U.S resorts within seconds. Ratings and Reviews 5.0 out of 5. https://itunes.app.com/us/app/snowpack/id1324334590?ls=1

mt=8



Friend Maps -

Co-Programmed with my wonderful classmate Kaitlyn Wright software for our iOS application Friend Maps in Swift, currently available on the apple iTunes app store. My direct role in this project included creating the Firebase Google Cloud Developers Real Time Database Infrastructure. Implemented the iOS features of user accounts, creating accounts with a profile photo, adding friends, and sorting this data with 500 Millisecond request response time from the user interface.

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/friendmaps/id1442017567#?platform=iphone



Photo Prediction -

Created and engineered all software for iOS application Photo Prediction in Swift, currently available on apple iTunes app store. Photo Prediction is an iOS application the uses ResNet-50 which is a deep residual network, to predict what is being seen by the camera.

https://apps.apple.com/app/id1464982664



fTunes -

Created and engineered all software for iOS application fTunes in swift. fTunes is an iOS music player application that will play random songs from your iTunes library filtered by whatever genre you choose



Digit Recognition -

Created and engineer all software for iOS application Digit Recognition in swift. Digit recognition uses Core ML, the vision framework and the MINST machine learning model to recognize handwriting directly from the touch drawing of the user.